Valeria Lobos-Ossandón

Researcher and Data Scientist

Diploma Software Engineering

About

Santiago Chile.

vlobos@fen.uchile.cl https://vlobosossandon.github.io/ fb://valeria.lobosossandon

Interests

I am specialized with data mining techniques and machine learning algorithms. The research topics with which I have worked on these issues are bibliometrics, Electronic Health Records, geocollaborative applications, crowdsourcing, web mining, and biometric data (eye-tracking electroencephalograms, and oximetry).

Languages

Native Spanish Speaker. Advanced English written and oral. Mandarin Chine & Italian notions

Programming

Python, Java, Visual Basic, C#, HTML.

Education

2016

	Diploma at Computer Science D	epartment.		
2016	Diploma Python for Data Science Standing 99% grade.	ce	Microsoft EDX	
2016	Diploma Scientific and Technica "How to write a good scientific pa	_	Principiae & Universidad de Chile	
2011-2016	2016 B.Sc. Engineering in Information Systems and			
	Management Control	Economy and Business Faculty, Universidad de Chile		
Graduated in the top-three in the class.				
2006-2009	Diploma English Oral and Writte	n Fluency	Instituto Chileno Norteamericano	

Universidad de Chile

Researcher & Data Scientist

Academic Experience

Graduated with honors.

Autumn 2017 Web Intelligence Centre	

Development of machine learning predictive models. Data mining techniques for E-health projects. Use of biometric data for predictive models.

Autumn 2016 Business Intelligence Center Researcher & Data Scientist

Development of machine learning predictive models. Development of text mining models for Spanish language text.

Spring 2015 Investigation Department, Economy and Business

Faculty, Universidad de ChileResearch Assistant

Use of bibliometric tools for reviewing academic's faculty performance.

Spring 2014 Control Management and Information Systems

Department, Universidad de Chile Research Assistant

Bibliometrics studies.

Teaching Experience

2017	Web Intelligence Teacher assistant.	Industrial Engineering Department. Universidad de Chil	le.
2013-2015	Algorithms and Programming Information Systems Department. Universidad de Chile. Teacher assistant. Visual Basic expertise		
2014-2015	Databases Teacher assistant. SQL expert	Information Systems Department. Universidad de Chilitise.	le.
2014	Technology and Information Universidad de Chile. Teacher assistant. SQL experts		nt.

Publications

2016	Computer Science Research in Artificial Intelligence	WCE 2016. London, UK
	J.M. Merigó, G. Zurita, V. Lobos-Ossandón	
2016	A Bibliometric Analysis of Journals in Educational Research J.M. Merigó, G. Zurita, V. Lobos-Ossandón	WCE 2016. London, UK
2017	A Real-Time Risk of Death Predictive Model in an Elderly Latin American Population B. Harnecker, V. Lobos-Ossandón, E. Tobar, J. D. Velásq	Working Paper uez.
2017	Predicting Cardiovascular Risk: A Combination of No and Framingham Index Variables M. Hernández, V. Lobos-Ossandón, I. Díaz, R. Ruiz, Velásquez.	Working Paper
2017	An Overview of the Most Cited Papers in Computer Science G. Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-For	Working Paper
2017	A Bibliometric Overview of Computer Science Journals G. Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-For	Working Paper
2017	Bibliometrics in Computer Science: An Institution Analysis G. Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-For	Working Paper
2017	Influential Journals in Educational Research: A Bibliometric Overview G. Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-For	Working Paper
2017	A Bibliometric Analysis of Highly Cited Articles in Educational Research G. Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-For	Working Paper
2017	A Bibliometric Overview of the First Ten Years of the Transactions on Learning Technologies G. Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-For	Working Paper
2017	The Gender Gap: Evidence from Eye-Tracker V. Lobos-Ossandón, J.D. Velásquez.	Work in Progress

2017	Leading Countries in Computer Science: A Bibliometric Overview G.Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-Forteza.	Work in Progress	
2017	Academic Research in Engineering: A Journal Analysis G.Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-Forteza.	Work in Progress	
2017	Most Cited Papers in Engineering: A Citation Analysis G.Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-Forteza.	Work in Progress	
2017	Most Productive Universities in Academic Research in Engineering G.Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-Forteza.	Work in Progress	
2017	Leading Countries in Engineering Research: A Bibliometric Overview Work in Progress G.Zurita, J.M. Merigó, V. Lobos-Ossandón, C. Mulet-Forteza.		
2017	Applied Mathematical Modelling ACTUALIZAR	Work in Progress	
2017	Fuzzy Sets and Systems ACTUALIZAR	Work in Progress	
2017	Materials & Design ACTUALIZAR	Work in Progress	
2017	The Gender Gap: Evidence from the Use of Eye-Tracker and EEGPresentation "Firt place winner of "Women's Day in Computing", organized by Association for Computing Machinery (ACM), in conjunction with the University of Chile and Pontificia of the Catholic University. He presented a study called "The Gender Difference: Evidence from the Use of Eye-Tracker and EEG", which studies eye movements and brain electrical potentials to differentiate the gender of website users."		
2016	Undescovering Chilean Polititians: Evidence from Text MiningPresentation "Speaker at "Women's Day in Computing", organized by the Association for Computing Machinery (ACM), in conjunction with the University of Chile and the Pontifical University of the Catholic University. He presented a study called "Big Data: Unmasking Chilean Politicians", which used Text Mining techniques to process more than five million news items from 25 national newspapers."		